http://raisingchildren.net.au/legal/terms-of-use

Skip to content
Skip to navigation
Welcome. You may be using this website to find balanced information about parenting, to find out about others’ experiences, or to be part of an online community.These terms and conditions of use form an agreement between you and Raising Children Network (Australia) Ltd, (RCN), whether you are sending us a message via the feedback forms, or simply browsing the website. They will inform you about your rights and obligations in using this website.The terms and conditions of use may change from time to time, so please re-visit every so often. Note that we are not required by law to contact you to inform you of changes. Please contact us if you have any questions about these terms and conditions of use.DisclaimerWarning: This website and the information it contains is not intended as a substitute for professional consultation with a qualified practitioner.Before relying on any information you find on raisingchildren.net.au, use common sense, make your own enquiries and seek professional opinion.Material in this publication is made available on the understanding that neither the Raising Children Network nor Commonwealth is providing professional advice. Before relying on any of the material in this site, readers should obtain appropriate professional advice. Views and recommendations of third parties, which are also included in this site, do not necessarily reflect the views of the Raising Children Network or the Commonwealth, or indicate a commitment to a particular course of action.Neither the Raising Children Network nor the Commonwealth accepts any responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of any material contained in this site. Additionally, the Raising Children Network and the Commonwealth disclaim all liability to any person relying wholly or partially upon any information presented in this site in respect of anything, and the consequences of anything, done or omitted to be done.You indemnify Raising Children Network and the organisations in the Raising Children Network (Australia) Ltd against each claim, action, proceeding, judgment, damage, loss, expense or liability incurred or suffered by, or brought, made or recovered against us or the organisations in the consortium in connection with any breach by you of these terms of use.The information provided in this website is intended for an Australian audience.If you use another site linked from this site:you do so at your own risk and acknowledge that we do not control or endorse those websites or their content;you will no longer be subject to the terms and conditions of this site but may be subject to the terms and conditions of the linked site.If you are from a particular cultural and/or religious background, you may be offended by some of the information and/or graphics found on this or linked sites.RCN endeavours to provide information sourced from reliable research based on peer reviewed journals, recognised texts, or government publications and therapeutic approaches that have demonstrated efficacy. The content on this site is periodically updated and reviewed for quality assurance using an editorial board and a review panel drawn from national and international expertise in early childhood, health and parenting. The authors reserve the right to modify the content of the website at any time.Any legal issues arising in relation to the use of this website will be dealt with under the laws of New South Wales, Australia. Illegal activity under those laws will be a violation of these terms, but as the website and the forums are accessible worldwide you should be aware that you could be prosecuted under the laws of other jurisdictions too.Personal information and your privacyRaising Children Network has a privacy policy that explains how we will treat your personal information in compliance with the Privacy Act 1988. You supply ‘personal information’ to us when you fill in an online registration form, subscribe to one of our email newsletters, complete a survey or poll, provide feedback on our content, submit parenting tips or email us.The personal information we collect is used to manage your subscriptions, contact you about your feedback, and keep in touch with you. When you register you give us a licence to deal with the postings as necessary to perform these technical and administrative functions.We will never give your personal information to any company or individual for commercial purposes.ComplaintsYour rights are taken seriously by our team. If you think your rights have been breached, or if you have a complaint about the Raising Children Network website, contact us so that we can investigate the issue and make sure it is resolved. Please write to the Complaints Officer explaining what you are concerned about and what steps, if any, you have taken to resolve the issue.You can either send an email to complaints or write a letter to:Raising Children Network Complaints Officer6th Floor SE BuildingRoyal Children’s Hospital Flemington RoadParkville Victoria 3052 AustraliaRaising Children Network reserves rightsYour message may be used by Raising Children Network. In consideration for permitting you to access and use the information on this website, posting on a raisingchildren.net.au message board or using the ‘Share Your Story’ link gives Raising Children Network a non-exclusive, perpetual, irrevocable, royalty-free, worldwide licence to reproduce, communicate, re-publish, edit, adapt or otherwise use your postings as we see fit, including the right to sublicense to others at our discretion. You also give us a licence to deal with the postings as necessary to perform technical, content and administrative functions in running the forums.  This includes any ‘moral rights’ you may have, therefore you consent to Raising Children Network editing, modifying or adapting your postings, or combining them with other works or postings to be used at Raising Children Network’s discretion as part of these above licenses whether or not you are attributed as the author of the postings.From time to time we may want to highlight a parent story or experience (provided by you by following the “Share Your Story” link or otherwise) and may publish your message elsewhere on the Raising Children Website. In this case, we may attribute authorship with permission, and generally would do so, but we are not obliged to. We will protect your privacy by ensuring that you are not personally identifiable from your posting, unless we obtain your prior written approval. For more information see our privacy policy.Copyright and acknowledgementsRaising Children Network reserves all intellectual property rights, including copyright and trade marks in the Raising Children Network website. Raising Children Network owns or has licensed from third parties the intellectual property used in this website. You may print single copies of any pages of this website for your own personal and non-commercial use but must not otherwise reproduce any material on this website in any form without permission.Requests and enquiries concerning reproduction and rights should be addressed to the Rights Management Officer at Raising Children Network.Last updated or reviewed25-09-2018
